Now, your machine learning system will make mistakes.
Seu sistema de aprendizado de máquina cometerá erros.
It's important to understand what these errors look like and how they might
É importante entender esses erros e como eles podem
affect the user experience that's driven by the output of your machine learning model.
afetar a experiência do usuário baseada nos resultados do seu modelo.
In this module, we'll discuss some of the ways in which you can
Neste módulo, vamos discutir algumas formas
evaluate inclusion as you're developing and testing your machine learning model.
de avaliar inclusão ao desenvolver e testar o modelo de aprendizado de máquina.
One of the key things to really know,
Uma coisa importante
which will help in understanding inclusion and how to
que ajudará você a entender a inclusão
introduce inclusion across different subgroups within your data,
e como incluí-la em diferentes subgrupos de dados
is by understanding the confusion matrix.
é entender a matriz de confusão.
While you may be familiar with evaluating your model over the entire dataset,
Você pode saber como avaliar o modelo com base em todo o grupo de dados,
it's also important to evaluate your model over subgroups.
mas é importante avaliar o modelo com base em subgrupos.
So, instead of just looking at how your model performs overall over your entire dataset,
Então, em vez de ver o desempenho geral do modelo com todo o conjunto de dados,
we'll focus instead on breaking the performance down to
vamos nos concentrar em dividir o desempenho
the subgroup that you wish to improve performance on.
em subgrupos para os quais você quer melhorar o desempenho.
For example, suppose you're doing face detection.
Por exemplo, imagine que você está fazendo uma detecção facial.
Essentially, you're building a machine learning model to
Você está criando um modelo de aprendizado de máquina
say whether or not there is a human face in a photograph.
que define se há um rosto humano em uma foto ou não.
This is not necessarily an easy problem.
Isso não é necessariamente um problema fácil.
Your subgroups might be men, women,
Seus subgrupos podem ser homens, mulheres,
adults, children, people with hair,
adultos, crianças, pessoas com cabelo,
people who are bald.
pessoas carecas.
You want to look at the performance of your model across
Você pode ver o desempenho do seu modelo
all these subgroups to identify areas of improvement.
em todos os subgrupos e identificar áreas para melhorar.
So, a common way that we evaluate performance in
Então, uma forma comum de avaliar o desempenho
machine learning is by using a confusion matrix.
em aprendizado de máquina é a matriz de confusão.
Now, there are other methods for other types of problems,
Há outros métodos para outros tipos de problemas,
but for the purposes of this module,
mas neste módulo
we'll focus on the confusion matrix to explain these points.
vamos focar na matriz de confusão para explicar esses pontos.
The idea is using the confusion matrix in order to look at inclusion.
A ideia é usar a matriz de confusão para entender a inclusão.
And you do this by first creating the confusion matrix,
Isso é feito criando a matriz de confusão
but you do so for every subgroup in your data,
para cada subgrupo de dados,
subgroups of what you're interested in measuring performance.
subgrupos para os quais você quer medir o desempenho.
Now, in the confusion matrix,
Na matriz de confusão,
you have comparisons between your labels, which, of course,
você tem comparações entre rótulos,
sometimes we don't necessarily have access to the ground truth.
porque às vezes não temos dados de referência.
But nevertheless, you're comparing those labels to your model predictions.
Mesmo assim, você está comparando rótulos às previsões do seu modelo.
From here, we look at the positives and negatives.
A partir disso, veremos os pontos positivos e negativos.
So in our labels, there are some things that are considered correct,
Em nossos rótulos, há algumas coisas consideradas corretas,
we will call those a positive label,
chamadas de rótulos positivos,
and there are some things that are considered incorrect,
e outras coisas consideradas incorretas,
and we call those negative labels.
chamadas de rótulos negativos.
On the machine learning side,
No aprendizado de máquina,
we have positive predictions about what there is and we
temos previsões positivas sobre o que está ali
We compare this in the confusion matrix in order to
Comparamos isso na matriz de confusão
starting with the true positives,
começando pelos verdadeiros positivos,
which is when the label says something is there and the model predicts it.
que é quando o rótulo diz que há algo e o modelo prevê.
So, in the case of face detection,
No caso de detecção facial,
a true positive would be when the model
um verdadeiro positivo seria quando o modelo
accurately predicted that there is a face in the image.
prevê corretamente que há um rosto na imagem.
Now, when the label says something exists and
Quando o rótulo diz que existe algo
a model doesn't predict it, that's a false negative.
e o modelo não prevê, isso é um falso negativo.
So, using the same face detection example,
Então, usando o mesmo exemplo de detecção facial,
the model does not predict there being a face in the image when
o modelo não prevê que há um rosto na imagem
When the label says it doesn't exist and your model also doesn't predict it,
Quando o rótulo diz que não há e o modelo não prevê,
that's what's called a true negative.
temos um verdadeiro negativo.
Basically, what that means is,
Basicamente, isso significa que,
using this face detection example,
usando o exemplo de detecção facial,
the model not predicting that the face is present in
a previsão do modelo de que não há um rosto na imagem
the image is correct because it's also not present in the label.
está correta, porque isso não está no rótulo.
And lastly, this is the false positive case,
Por fim, há o falso positivo,
where the label says there is no face but
quando o rótulo diz que não há um rosto,
the machine learning model predicts that there should be a face.
mas o modelo de aprendizado de máquina prevê que deve haver um rosto.
So, in this instance,
Então, nesse caso,
perhaps there is a statue in the image and
talvez haja uma estátua na imagem
the model falsely identifies that statue as having a face.
e o modelo identifique falsamente que a estátua tenha rosto.
But really, what I want you to focus in on
Mas é melhor você focar
Remember, false negatives are the things you incorrectly do not predict,
Lembre-se, falsos negativos são coisas que incorretamente não são previstas,
things you exclude when instead it should have been included,
coisas que você exclui que deveriam ser incluídas,
and false positives are things that you incorrectly predicted,
e falsos positivos são coisas que você prevê incorretamente,
things you include that aren't actually there in
coisas que você inclui, mas que não estão
the label and should have instead been excluded.
no rótulo e deveriam ter sido excluídas.
And these are often referred to as type I errors in type II errors in other domains.
Esses erros costumam ser chamados de tipo I e tipo II em outros locais.
But the cool thing about this sort of basic breakdown into
Mas o legal dessa divisão básica
four different kinds of matches to the label is that you
em quatro tipos de correspondências com os rótulos é que você
can start to calculate a ton of different metrics
pode começar a calcular vários tipos de métricas
that can be used to gauge the amount of inclusiveness in your model.
que podem ser usadas para medir a inclusividade do seu modelo.